Harsh Mohan Gajra

Herndon, VA,USA 20151 | 6073388922 | harsh.gajra@gmail.com

Objective

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience specializing in Java Development and Java frameworks like Jersey-Jax RS, Spring Boot and Hibernate . Possesses a MS in Computer Science from State University of New York, impeccable problem solving and software engineering skills, and excellent interpersonal skills. Looking for a challenging and interesting role in Software Development. I am part of core Software engineering team at Pype Inc , a Construction SaaS company raising over \$3 million dollars in funding.

Education

Master's in Computer Science - State University Of New York, Binghamton, August 2016 - May 2018 Bachelor of Computer Engineering - K.J.Somaiya College of Engineering, Mumbai, First class

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Programming

Languages, Design Patterns

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/harsh-gajra/ **GitHub**: https://github.com/HarshGajraSUNY

Technical Skills

Java 8 **Data Structures Eclipse** Amazon Web Services REST api AngularJS Git Gradle GitHub Jenkins CI/CD Spring Boot Jira MySQL Android JPA **Prototyping** API **GIMP**

Proof of Concepts Web Applications Design Patterns

Writing Java CSS Cloud Framework **HTML** JAX-RS Real-time **JavaScript** Restful Software NoSQL Software Development Node.is UI IDE J2ee DynamoDB NetBeans SQL

Code Review Java Software Development PL/SQL

GUI JDBC

Work Experience

Software Engineer - Pype Inc | Herndon, VA, USA , July 2018 - Present

- Backend software engineering, design and Development of new features for web applications using Java 8, Jersey JAX-RS REST api framework, Spring Boot, and MySQL as the database.
- Designing and developed internal software solutions for optimizing the business process followed by in-house Sales and Support teams thus saving the organization \$360,000 per year in costs and 15,000 man-hours per year.
- Full Stack development of a document management and turnover package software application using AngularJS,Html, css on frontend and Java 8, Jersey Rest api framework on backend and MySql as database.
- Designed the data model and developed the backend code for an Email Cadence software tool using Java 8, Spring Boot, JPA and MvSQL database.
- Managed, mentored and gave work assignments and conducted code reviews for junior software engineers.
- Algorithm Development: Design, Analyze and implement algorithms in core Java for solving various use cases across the software products of the company.
- Writing integrations of current applications with externals cloud services e.g AWS S3.
- Production support of Applications: Provided L3 Production support for company's software products.
- Develop, implement and/or improve the application production support knowledge management repository to ensure all are documented, process & procedures are clear and periodic reviews are conducted .
- DevOps: Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using Jenkins and GitLab.

- Researching and development of proof of concepts for new product development using Google cloud console, AWS, GIMP and Java 8.
- Writing automations for the manual tasks performed by Customer Support and Success Teams within the company's software products.

Software Engineer | CereLabs | Mumbai Area, India, February 2015 – July 2016

- Developed a Speech-to-Intent Recognition Software Web Application in the Healthcare domain using technologies like Html ,CSS,JavaScript and Core Java 8,Spring Boot and Hibernate.
- Developed the front end using JSF, Angular JS, HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, JSP, CSS, and JQuery.
- Integrated Google Speech API to Convert Speech to Text and send the Text data as Wit Message API to Facebook's Wit.ai platform for 'Intent Recognition'.
- Wrote the code in Node.js on AWS Lambda for trigger response from AWS DynamoDB as NoSQL datastore.
- Performed end to end testing of the final product and identified possible flaws.
- Mentored a team of three interns on research projects in Face Recognition and Asset tracking.
- Prepared Business Use-Case Analysis on Numenta's Intelligent Computing Framework Nupic for new business opportunities in Artificial Intelligence Domain
- Bestowed as "Internal Champion" of the company.

Software Engineer (Part Time) | Mad Infotech | Mumbai Area,India, January 2012 – January 2011

- Involved in designing and creating the Database Tables and Views.
- Developed the static webpages in HTML and CSS based on the given designs.
- Writing well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices.
- Creating website layout/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS practices.
- Integrating data from various back-end services and databases.
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs.
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and apply them into operations and activities.
- Developed the backend components in Java 8.
- Inspection/Review of quality deliverables such as Design Documents.
- Wrote SQL Scripts, Stored procedures and SQL Loader to load reference data.
- Create and maintain software documentation.

Paper Publications

- Paper: Credit card Fraud Detection and Prevention Using Perceptron Training Algorithm.
- Journal: International Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication, Apr 2015
- Link: https://ijritcc.org/index.php/ijritcc/article/view/4182/4182